The wild, untold story of OZploitation!
Not Quite Hollywood is a comedy, documentary film directed by Mark Hartley.
As Australian cinema broke through to international audiences in the 1970s through respected art house films like Peter Weir's "Picnic At
Hanging Rock," a new underground of low-budget exploitation filmmakers were turning out considerably less highbrow fare.
Documentary filmmaker Mark Hartley explores this unbridled era of sex and violence, complete with clips from
some of the scene's most outrageous flicks and interviews with the renegade filmmakers themselves.
Self, played by Phillip Adams.
Self, played by Glory Annen.
Self, played by Christine Amor.
Self, played by Victoria Anoux.
Self, played by Briony Behets.
Self, played by Steve Bisley.
Not Quite Hollywood: The Wild, Untold Story of Ozploitation!
is a 2008 documentary film about the Australian New Wave
of 1970s and 1980s low-budget cinema.
The film was written and directed by Mark Hartley, who interviewed over eighty Australian, American and British actors, directors, screenwriters and producers, including
Quentin Tarantino, Brian Trenchard-Smith, Jamie Lee Curtis, Dennis Hopper, George Lazenby, George Miller, Barry Humphries, Stacy Keach, Glory Annen, John D.
Lamond, John Seale and Roger Ward.
Hartley spent several years writing a detailed research document, which served to some
degree as a script for the film, about the New Wave era of Australian cinema.
It focused on the commonly overlooked "Ozploitation" films—mainly filled with sex, horror and violence—which critics and
film historians considered vulgar and offensive, often excluded from Australia's "official film history".
Hartley approached Quentin Tarantino, a longtime "Ozploitation" fan who had dedicated his 2003 film Kill
Bill to the exploitation genre, and Tarantino agreed to help get the project off the ground.
Hartley then spent an additional five years interviewing subjects and editing the combined
250 hours of interviews and original stock footage into a 100-minute film.
Not Quite Hollywood, which premiered at the 2008 Melbourne International Film Festival, did not perform well at the box office upon its Australia-wide release,
but garnered universally positive reviews from critics and a nomination for "Best Documentary" at the 2008 Australian Film Institute Awards.
The tone is lighthearted.